<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>student choice | btihen</title>
    <link>https://btihen.me/tags/student-choice/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://btihen.me/tags/student-choice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>student choice</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 14:05:38 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://btihen.me/img/btihen_landing_page.png</url>
      <title>student choice</title>
      <link>https://btihen.me/tags/student-choice/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smallify to Learn Effectively</title>
      <link>https://btihen.me/post_edu/edgility_btihen_smallify/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 14:05:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://btihen.me/post_edu/edgility_btihen_smallify/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://peakchallenges.ch/blog/edgility_pmagnuson_transparency&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Transparency article&lt;/a&gt;, there is an important interaction between having the “big picture” (having a goal and some expectations along the way) and knowing “what to do next” (a feeling of workability and progress). This article explores how to establish both by creating an effective self-guided learning strategy for students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In EDgility we encourage student self-determination. Student choice and understanding the big picture are critical components to cultivate self-determination. They need to understand the big picture in order to exercise real choice. To support them, I like to offer students projects with broad goals. The big general goal starts the process of smallifying, because they will have to smallify in order to make progress. The students first explore the field just enough to find ideas that interest them, to pick their own specific goal, and to find a purpose or context for that goal.  It is important at this stage that the student’s goals already include a complication / design compromise consistent with the overall goal. For example, students may choose to build a cargo boat that saves energy, but it must also be stable in waves. Commercially, their boat is only better if it is effective at the overall goal (staying afloat) and good at a new specific goal (saving energy). Students must think broadly and understand the context of their project in actual use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first step generally creates a lot of enthusiasm (and ideas) as the students create a storyline, a new identity, and an organization to support their mission. The story line and organization need to be attractive to them and others, both to support their motivation and to make for a good sales pitch at the end of the unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two classes that started with big goals that required smallifying into many workable steps were the “Boat Design” and “Robot Gardeners” classes.  I’ve written about those elsewhere, see e.g. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://btihen.me/publication/ecis_designed_to_float_your_boat_article/&#34;&gt;boat design in ECIS Global Insights&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://btihen.me/publication/las_spotlight_robot_gardener/&#34;&gt;Robot Gardeners in Spotlight&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step in smallifying is for the students to figure out the most important aspects needed to accomplish the big goals. I call this &lt;strong&gt;distilling&lt;/strong&gt; the essence of the topic in relation to their goal. For example, in the boat design class, all boat designs must understand buoyancy (flotation), and depending on the boat specialty and safety features, two or three other concepts will be important, i.e., students who choose to build a speedboat will need excellent fluid efficiency and perhaps also stability while turning. Learning to discover the important aspects of a large complex field and to find the critical aspects relating to one’s goals is an important life skill in almost all aspects of life. It is, in fact, a skill that transcends the specific content of the class - and therefore lifeworthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give the students only a short amount of time to do these first two steps (perhaps one or two classes total). This prevents analysis paralysis. Besides, not having time to fully understand a field before starting gives the students permission to adjust as they explore their topic. Learning to manage and adjust projects as you learn and progress is known as &lt;strong&gt;agile management&lt;/strong&gt; - another useful life-skill in our quickly evolving world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point the students start the iterative smallification of concrete actionable steps to learn and progress toward the goal. These small steps are exploratory and safe. Safe means that the step is small enough that it isn’t upsetting if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work on the first try and safe means that the teacher is neutral about successful and unsuccessful steps. &lt;strong&gt;Exploring and learning is what is celebrated.&lt;/strong&gt; Under no condition can mistakes be punished or made a point of shame. Without feeling safe about errors and unknowns, smallifying and creative learning is almost impossible. It will take time for most students to trust this environment, thus initially, expect students to be reluctant to smallify in order to explore all the unknowns inherent in big messy goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figuring out the next workable step happens as the student progresses - students are not working from a large, clear plan that maps out each step at the beginning of the project. I do give students who have never worked this way a few introductory steps to get them started.  Once underway, students gain confidence and generally have enough experience to find the next workable step - as they progress. Here’s a concrete example of smallifying, based on building a racing catamaran that is stable while turning at speed might be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;configure your computer with the software to print on a 3-D printer;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;design and print a box (or any simple shape);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;print the above shape, but make it hollow (learn to subtract a shape);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;print the above hollowed shape joined with a second shape; if the first shape is a box, add a cone, sphere, pyramid, etc (this requires addition and translation);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etc. (now the students have enough basics to keep learning and progressing).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Bill Rankin said in several keynote addresses, you learn to cook by cooking. In fact, you learn almost anything by doing it. You have to jump in and start, or “get cooking.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, a student who chooses to build a rescue boat will have a different set of small steps, but common to both boats is learning to work incrementally and building on the next workable small step toward the goal. This is a powerful learning technique that builds confidence in students&#39; ability to learn and be successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the students get the hang of this process of moving from the big picture, identifying a few critical aspects, and smallifiying their project into small workable steps, they have effectively learned how to learn and self-correct as they move toward a large complex goal. This meta-aspect of the learning process and its deliberate practice may in the long run be a lifeworthy skill that goes far beyond the specific content of a single class. Engineering classes such as the Boat Design class example here work well. So, too, do classes in art and other areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caution:&lt;/strong&gt; Smallification happens in &lt;strong&gt;small&lt;/strong&gt; chunks (one or two steps at a time maximum). In the tech world we call this planning at the last responsible moment, but fundamentally, it is about figuring out the next workable thing when the students have enough information to see that next step. This prevents the feeling that the big goal is just too overwhelming. Students who have never worked this way will need some smallifying guidance. For example, in the Boat Design class, I gave students a few steps to get started and I give the details of the final assessment. (I like a public demonstration and company pitch.)  As a teacher you may want to step through a project to be more confident in the timing, practice the smallifying, etc, but be careful not to give away more than needed and avoid at all costs big and detailed plans! The fun and exploration is a central feature of a motivating and educational experience for the students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally, creating a learning environment where having the big picture and exploring the details along the way can create an uplifting educational journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploration in the Classroom</title>
      <link>https://btihen.me/post_edu/edgility_btihen_exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 16:57:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://btihen.me/post_edu/edgility_btihen_exploration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fun and a sense of adventure can be crucial to classroom engagement and learning. Cultivating a sense of adventure is similar to encouraging an atmosphere of playfulness and joy of learning. This can be quite straightforward when students are allowed to create their own goals and their own context for the goals within the curriculum. Of course, any good adventure can’t be too easy. It’s the teacher’s job to make sure a project has no obvious, googleable answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We might worry that making the project hard and beyond what the students know how to do could be unfair or even unjust. This might be true. When students are used to the mindset of getting things right the first time, it is difficult for them to take an idea and ‘play’ with it until something works. This adjustment takes some time, but once they get the hang of it, students enjoy exploring and they learn quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I most enjoy  observing how students learn resilience through ‘playing’ with ideas and trying different options until they find a solution. In fact, in today’s world it may be more important to learn resilience, persistence, and finding the next small workable step in order to progress toward a goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course creating an environment where exploration can thrive requires not doing a few things, too - such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not judging or criticizing mistakes or rework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not judging the work or its qualities, instead let the kids cultivate their own pride and ownership (the minimum quality tests need clear, objective and observable)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not celebrating the answers, but celebrating the exploratory and learning aspects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not requiring that every student have the same depth of knowledge in each part of the project. It&amp;rsquo;s important to define baseline knowledge they all need to have - but after that they need to be free to explore more deeply what the student finds interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To encourage exploration we have found that the following the guidance for a growth mindset is very helpful:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Praise the grit and perseverance of arriving at a workable solution;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cultivate the mindset of finding the next workable thing to try, even when there is no clear path to the goal; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage / expect (maybe even require) rework and changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a practical note, it is important to create projects that are complex and have some built-in conflict that requires balancing and tradeoffs. This is important for several reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Without trade-offs, a problem isn’t realistic and can be too easily googled.  The problem must be challenging enough or it isn’t engaging (but it needs to be workable).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having to resolve a conflict or resolve tradeoffs and still arrive at one&amp;rsquo;s goals requires students to really go into depth and learn that aspect extra well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; In the world of engineering, it is important to have a solid generalist understanding of the field (like the basic required information tested at school), but that is rarely enough for most teams. It is important to be a specialist in at least one area of interest &amp;ndash; these are called ‘T’ shaped engineers - engineers that have gone deep into two areas are even more valuable and are called ‘π’ shaped engineers. I’m advocating for creating projects (and classroom environments) in school that cultivate the same generalist / specialist mindset that is often expected in graduate school and professional lives. Art curriculums have long taught the core skills and ideas and then expected students to explore and expand upon their interests. Imagine how engaging education could be when all aspects of schools encouraged choice and exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching this way can be uncomfortable for teachers who may traditionally have felt that they need to operate as the expert who knows everything. To model the idea, however, that you don’t have to know everything, it is actually helpful not to know everything. In fact, you cannot give students a quick answer, which cuts off their chance to think through the problem, and instead you explore with the students and model how to learn and resolve difficult problems. The teacher must simply understand the basics and vocabulary of the field to help students interpret what they find.  Of course the teacher must also be comfortable modeling exploring the unknown with the kids.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demos and Feedback in the Classroom</title>
      <link>https://btihen.me/publication/tieonline_demos_and_collaborative_feedback_in_classroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://btihen.me/publication/tieonline_demos_and_collaborative_feedback_in_classroom/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pull vs Push: Student Centric</title>
      <link>https://btihen.me/publication/tieonline_pull_vs_push/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://btihen.me/publication/tieonline_pull_vs_push/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patient Explanations Lead to Good Things</title>
      <link>https://btihen.me/publication/las_spotlight_patient_explanations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://btihen.me/publication/las_spotlight_patient_explanations/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designed to Float your Boat</title>
      <link>https://btihen.me/publication/ecis_designed_to_float_your_boat_article/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://btihen.me/publication/ecis_designed_to_float_your_boat_article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- &lt;iframe allowfullscreen allow=&#34;fullscreen&#34; style=&#34;border:none;width:100%;height:326px;&#34; src=&#34;https://issuu.com/ecischools/docs/globalinsights6&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student boat (before 3-D printing)
&lt;img src=&#34;student_katamaran_boat.png&#34; alt=&#34;Student Katamaran Boat&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student boat (with code)
&lt;img src=&#34;student_boat_with_code.png&#34; alt=&#34;Student Katamaran Boat&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student boat (with code)
&lt;img src=&#34;blank_burndown_chart.png&#34; alt=&#34;Blank Burndown Chart&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student Retrospective Guide
&lt;img src=&#34;boat_retrospectives.png&#34; alt=&#34;Student Retrospective Guide&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
