<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education | btihen</title>
    <link>https://btihen.github.io/categories/education/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://btihen.github.io/categories/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Education</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 16:57:16 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://btihen.github.io/images/logo_hu0d53a2a03d4a529abcdd0318d0f2ad50_8175_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://btihen.github.io/categories/education/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploration in the Classroom</title>
      <link>https://btihen.github.io/post_edu/learning_loop_exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 16:57:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://btihen.github.io/post_edu/learning_loop_exploration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fun and a sense of adventure can be crucial to classroom engagement and learning. Cultivating a sense of adventure is similar to encouraging an atmosphere of playfulness and joy of learning. This can be quite straightforward when students are allowed to create their own goals and their own context for the goals within the curriculum. Of course, any good adventure can’t be too easy. It’s the teacher’s job to make sure a project has no obvious, googleable answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We might worry that making the project hard and beyond what the students know how to do could be unfair or even unjust. This might be true. When students are used to the mindset of getting things right the first time, it is difficult for them to take an idea and ‘play’ with it until something works. This adjustment takes some time, but once they get the hang of it, students enjoy exploring and they learn quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I most enjoy  observing how students learn resilience through ‘playing’ with ideas and trying different options until they find a solution. In fact, in today’s world it may be more important to learn resilience, persistence, and finding the next small workable step in order to progress toward a goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course creating an environment where exploration can thrive requires not doing a few things, too - such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not judging or criticizing mistakes or rework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not judging the work or its qualities, instead let the kids cultivate their own pride and ownership (the minimum quality tests need clear, objective and observable)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not celebrating the answers, but celebrating the exploratory and learning aspects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not requiring that every student have the same depth of knowledge in each part of the project. It&amp;rsquo;s important to define baseline knowledge they all need to have - but after that they need to be free to explore more deeply what the student finds interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To encourage exploration we have found that the following the guidance for a growth mindset is very helpful:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Praise the grit and perseverance of arriving at a workable solution;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cultivate the mindset of finding the next workable thing to try, even when there is no clear path to the goal; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage / expect (maybe even require) rework and changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a practical note, it is important to create projects that are complex and have some built-in conflict that requires balancing and tradeoffs. This is important for several reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Without trade-offs, a problem isn’t realistic and can be too easily googled.  The problem must be challenging enough or it isn’t engaging (but it needs to be workable).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having to resolve a conflict or resolve tradeoffs and still arrive at one&amp;rsquo;s goals requires students to really go into depth and learn that aspect extra well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; In the world of engineering, it is important to have a solid generalist understanding of the field (like the basic required information tested at school), but that is rarely enough for most teams. It is important to be a specialist in at least one area of interest &amp;ndash; these are called ‘T’ shaped engineers - engineers that have gone deep into two areas are even more valuable and are called ‘π’ shaped engineers. I’m advocating for creating projects (and classroom environments) in school that cultivate the same generalist / specialist mindset that is often expected in graduate school and professional lives. Art curriculums have long taught the core skills and ideas and then expected students to explore and expand upon their interests. Imagine how engaging education could be when all aspects of schools encouraged choice and exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching this way can be uncomfortable for teachers who may traditionally have felt that they need to operate as the expert who knows everything. To model the idea, however, that you don’t have to know everything, it is actually helpful not to know everything. In fact, you cannot give students a quick answer, which cuts off their chance to think through the problem, and instead you explore with the students and model how to learn and resolve difficult problems. The teacher must simply understand the basics and vocabulary of the field to help students interpret what they find.  Of course the teacher must also be comfortable modeling exploring the unknown with the kids.
ploring the unknown with the kids.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explore, Uplift and Reflect</title>
      <link>https://btihen.github.io/post_edu/explore_uplift_reflect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 15:16:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://btihen.github.io/post_edu/explore_uplift_reflect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Basically a mix of having the kids build on their strengths, &lt;strong&gt;exploring&lt;/strong&gt; the doing project based with and goal and within a context of the student&amp;rsquo;s choice.  The project-work uses many agile processes*, one step outside their knowledge/comfort,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agility in this context means small-teams that work with small aspects of a bigger objective and build their knowledge / project iteratively and reflect (on demo suggestions (feedback) AND their own learning process) to inform the next iteration and enjoy the exploration of knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;teachers-responsibilities--activities&#34;&gt;Teacher&amp;rsquo;s Responsibilities &amp;amp; Activities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPLIFT&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;BUILD SUCCESS AND CONFIDENCE&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; &lt;strong&gt;I personally like to borrow from the concept of the Hero&amp;rsquo;s Journey&lt;/strong&gt; - Help the student have a context and need to learn &amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;apply&lt;/strong&gt; knowledge to the point where they can SOLVE A COMPLEX CHALLENGE to meet the goal within the context of the learning objectives of the class (or unit).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uplifted Atmosphere&lt;/strong&gt; - guide kids to encourage strengths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;re-enforce&lt;/em&gt; activities that builds the student&amp;rsquo;s confidence and joy in learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;re-direct&lt;/em&gt; distracting /destructive activities toward helpful actions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;exploration&lt;/em&gt; create an atmosphere where learning can be fun, meaningful and exploratory (like young kids) and not stressful and time-based&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural Assessment &amp;amp; Motivation&lt;/strong&gt; - whenever possible &amp;amp; allowed - I avoid grading, assessing and correcting students.  Instead, I encourage nature assessments and motivation.
&lt;em&gt;For example, while building boats, have a pool and criteria for &amp;ldquo;tracking&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;load&amp;rdquo;, etc. and have the students test the boat in the pool - where everyone can see and test the qualities.  To that end, I find it very helpful if the students work will be publicly viewed and seen by others - preferably with the students present to &amp;ldquo;show&amp;rdquo; their product &amp;amp; experience the pride (or embarrassment in their work).  That&amp;rsquo;s often much more ownership than a grade.&lt;/em&gt;
If a state or other external final exam like an AP test is part of the course &amp;ndash; then I suggest after covering the material in the project based way &amp;ndash; then spend the last part of the class doing practice exams until the students are comfortable with the exam aspects of the knowledge.  This mixed approach has been very successful in teaching AP Computer Science (nearly all students received the top score 19 of 20 students).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teaching Activities&lt;/strong&gt; - guide kids to learn the materials (rarely instruct)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;guide students to other students who can help them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;help the students smallify their work to find something they can research &amp;amp; solve (the next doable step just beyond their skill-level)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;help the students with keywords, concepts and vocabulary to do the research for their next step&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;help the students understand and interpret their research they found but don&amp;rsquo;t fully understand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;help the students apply their research they&amp;rsquo;ve understood conceptually, but unsure how to implement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;students-responsibilities--activities&#34;&gt;Student&amp;rsquo;s Responsibilities &amp;amp; Activities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choice&lt;/strong&gt; - of goals and context within the context of the learning objectives of the class (or unit).  &lt;em&gt;For example to teach middle school students 3-D Analytical Geometry &amp;amp; Fluid Dynamics - students create companies and design a boat of their choice (and print versions of it as they refine it).  Each boat will need a specialty with a specialty (stability, comfort for people, speed, tracking, efficiency, load, &amp;hellip;) and can overcome some adversity (wind, waves, currents, &amp;hellip;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Context&lt;/strong&gt; - students need to create a context they own for their chosen goal.  &lt;em&gt;This means creating a story (an explanation / real or imagined) for the importance of their chosen goal. For example when teaching Earth Sciences students could choose to make an Earthquake alarm system to help people in stay safe.  To that end they also have to consider the consequences of their system if people rely on it - and choose at least one failure condition they can mitigate.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural Assessment&lt;/strong&gt; - Students need to learn to take ownership for tracking their own knowledge, resources and quality.  &lt;em&gt;To that end, I avoid personally telling them what to correct, instead they need to get peer-reviews, do demos and get feedback from others and assess their work against their stated goals.  To that end I almost always require a public display of their work with them present.  Either a presentation or demos where people come by and they demo / explain their work.  I also have them practice within the class with each other - where they can see the quality and ideas of others with enough time to adjust their own work to meet their own standards or pride and avoid a sense of embarrassment (or not).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Demos &amp;amp; Constructive Feedback&lt;/strong&gt; - ideally I have the kids have a project journal and demo notes and reflections need to be recorded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demos are IMPORTANT - putting students in the learners driver seat.  Students need to learn to get / ask for (&lt;strong&gt;pull&lt;/strong&gt;) their feedback to assess and adjust the quality and progress of their work (with help from the &lt;em&gt;Natural Assessment as a reality check &amp;ndash; not the teacher - &amp;lsquo;What does the water say?&#39;&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students must learn to give &amp;amp; hear &amp;amp; accept feedback in their work.  To that end there are 4 rules to make this work - with more experience these can be loosened some:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;plan&lt;/strong&gt; what and how to present the demo (&amp;amp; what the feedback might be - both likes and changes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;present the demo &amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;receiving feedback&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;listen &amp;amp; take notes&lt;/strong&gt; (no challenges - keep it safe to &lt;strong&gt;give feedback&lt;/strong&gt;, further explanations or clarifications of misunderstandings - simply note ones reaction and reflect on how to improve the demo - theres no problem with doing a second demo with another group if the first group didn&amp;rsquo;t understand).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Giving Feedback&lt;/strong&gt; - includes two aspects:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what is &lt;strong&gt;liked&lt;/strong&gt; and how that matches what is understood about the group&amp;rsquo;s goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what they think would make the work &lt;strong&gt;even better&lt;/strong&gt; (if something should change then is needs to be worded as - &amp;ldquo;I like this &amp;lsquo;pointy bow&amp;rsquo; and think it would be even better with a rounded bow&amp;rdquo;) - constructive and positive feedback (this takes practice &amp;ndash; kids (and teachers) are not well versed in &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Pixar&amp;rsquo;s yes and &amp;hellip;&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; feedback process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;using a suggestion&lt;/strong&gt; each project must accept at least &lt;strong&gt;ONE&lt;/strong&gt; suggestion from another group (and credit them) and explain how they made the suggestion their own and integrated it into the project.  Without this - they cannot submit the project (its incomplete)!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploration&lt;/strong&gt; - kids should learn to enjoy learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DO VERY little direct instruction (if any) - have the kids explore until they get a bit stuck (but don&amp;rsquo;t make them beg for help, just be patient and help them get unstuck - DON&amp;rsquo;T TELL THEM SOLUTIONS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learning need to change (as much as possible) from an external &amp;ldquo;death march&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong&gt;pushed&lt;/strong&gt; by the curriculum, but instead turned into a lean &lt;strong&gt;pull&lt;/strong&gt; system by the students own needs, interests and desire to fulfill their own chosen goals within their chosen context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ideally students track what they research and learn in the project journal.  Then all kids on the team have access to all the info (&amp;amp; is responsible to know what is known by others on the team - that is the homework - to know what others have done and be aware and understand it).  Occasionally, I look at the journal and ask other kids in the group to explain what another has researched and if the kids doesn&amp;rsquo;t know the material then the &amp;lsquo;researcher&amp;rsquo; is responsible to ensure the others on team &amp;lsquo;catch up&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Path&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;The Hero&amp;rsquo;s Journey &amp;amp; Smallify&lt;/strong&gt; - initially students are unfamilier with solving big complex problems without one clear &amp;lsquo;Googable&amp;rsquo; answer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;smallify&lt;/strong&gt; - students need to learn to find the next workable step just beyond their knowledge &amp;ndash; but doable (initially kids need help with this!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;small enough&lt;/strong&gt; - where its easy to have false starts, make lots of changes and explore and after feedback &amp;ndash; make changes without being upset at the invested time.  &lt;strong&gt;Small enough means that it is fun to explore and make changes!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hero&amp;rsquo;s Journey&lt;/strong&gt; - each project needs to involve complexity &lt;em&gt;(that has no one right solution)&lt;/em&gt; but involves a complex compromise to arrive at one&amp;rsquo;s goals.  This helps the students really learn the depth of the material and the compromises needed to accomplish their goals. (there have been recent studies showing that people only fully understand a topic and its related implications when they go through process of exploring complex compromises)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reflection &amp;amp; Change&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;another form of reflection - done ideally daily, they asses their progress (initially I like to review their burn-down on their way out at the end of class with them and help them reflect on and verbalize what skills they are using to make progress &amp;amp; contemplate if its possible to build even more on those strengths and to reflect on whats hinder them (&amp;amp; see if they can replace that activity with something more helpful).  Over time I like to encourage the kid to just update me their progress and reflections on their way out of class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;students need to get regular feedback on each phase of their work (ideally at least weekly) &amp;amp; at some point each group&amp;rsquo;s project must have at least on change inspired by feedback from another group or individual outside their group - and credit that person / group. Even if &amp;amp; in-fact ideally - they take the idea and adapt it to their needs needs and goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kanban Usage</title>
      <link>https://btihen.github.io/post_edu/kanban_usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 19:25:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://btihen.github.io/post_edu/kanban_usage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kanban is a visual way to track your tasks and your progress.  Many people find this helpful way to to show yourself, your parents and teachers what work needs to be done.  Ideally, this is done on a large screen, sheet of paper, or whiteboard - so that it is obvious and easily seen as a reminder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;example.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kanban&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;status-tracking&#34;&gt;Status Tracking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simplest &lt;code&gt;statuses&lt;/code&gt; would be: &lt;strong&gt;To-Do, Doing, Done&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;see example image&gt; --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some teacher often require a draft &lt;code&gt;Review&lt;/code&gt; before final submissions, engineers use a similar column &lt;code&gt;Review&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Demo&lt;/code&gt;.  Generally, this is a good idea to check your work with peers, parents or your teacher before handing in your work &amp;ndash; so we suggest a &lt;code&gt;Review&lt;/code&gt; column before done. So now the statuses would be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To-Do, Doing, Review, Done&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;see example image&gt; --&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;swim-lanes-tracking-multiple-classes--projects&#34;&gt;Swim-lanes (tracking multiple classes / projects)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally when using this technique you keep the number of simultaneous tasks &lt;strong&gt;(WIP)&lt;/strong&gt; to a minimum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of simultaneous tasks is called &lt;code&gt;work-in-progress&lt;/code&gt; or abbreviated as &lt;code&gt;WIP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Education, unfortunately, expects a lot of simultaneous tasks within a variety of classes.  To address this we can use &lt;code&gt;swim-lanes&lt;/code&gt; to track our priorities with a jumble of independent projects (classes).  For example: we might have swim-lanes for: English, Mathematics, Science, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, we will try only allow &lt;strong&gt;ONE task&lt;/strong&gt; in your &lt;code&gt;doing&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;review&lt;/code&gt; boxes for each swim-lane / class.  &lt;em&gt;(This is called a WIP Limit of 1).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;example_w_swimlane.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kanban_w_swimlanes&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tasks&#34;&gt;Tasks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tasks Cards should have critical reminder information on them. Refrain from putting extra information on the card, the card should be clean and simple to read - it is a reminder of work to do NOT a full description of the assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the critical information I include on a personal Kanban card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt; - Big bold text (upper left corner)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt; - a very short reminder of what to do - ideally in 4 to 5 words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Class&lt;/strong&gt; - in case of confusion, I write the class / swim-lane (lower left corner)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due Date&lt;/strong&gt; - Big bold Text (lower right corner)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start Date&lt;/strong&gt; - use this to schedule small tasks of a large project - which can be used to slowly make progress on a large task (I call this smallifying).  This is a very important skill to ensure continued progress on large projects in a timely way.  I put this just above the &lt;code&gt;Due Date&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;see example image of a variety of tasks on a post-it with assignment below include a large task smallified&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of a Kanban in use with tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;example_w_tasks.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kanban_w_tasks&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;usage&#34;&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to use A3 paper and small post-it notes to add tasks.  Here is our recommended blank Kanban - where you can write in your classes.  Put your most important classes (in the IB these would be your &lt;strong&gt;High Level&lt;/strong&gt; courses) at the top. Use a timebox on long tasks that need to move forward, but are too big to do in one work session &amp;ndash; this is especially important when you have multiple tasks that need to be accomplished on a give day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timebox&lt;/strong&gt; - is a time limit that you won&amp;rsquo;t exceed for a given tasks in order to keep all tasks on schedule.  We suggest 25 to 35 minute timeboxes with small 5 minute breaks between tasks.  Every 4 timeboxes take a longer 15 minute break. This is called the pomodoro technique for full details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VFW3Ld7JO0w&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To best use a Kanban board, you should follow the following ritual:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prioritize your work&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; when you sit down to work, spend the first 5 minutes reviewing the Kanban board:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First assess what in the &lt;em&gt;priority&lt;/em&gt; classes needs to be done in order meet assignment deadlines &lt;em&gt;(for long tasks set a &lt;strong&gt;timebox&lt;/strong&gt; so you make progress but can keep all your other tasks moving too)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second assess what needs to be started in &lt;em&gt;priority&lt;/em&gt; classes to stay on track with larger projects. If you already have a task in that classes &lt;code&gt;doing&lt;/code&gt; box then schedule that task to be done ASAP so that you can start the next task.  &lt;em&gt;This is important&lt;/em&gt; a common Kanban saying is:_ **START FINISHING TASKS, stop starting unfinished tasks!**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do your work&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; respect your priorities and your timeboxes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE YOUR KANBAN&lt;/strong&gt; - End five to ten minutes before your time is up (set an alarm if needed) and &lt;strong&gt;update&lt;/strong&gt; your tasks to their new status boxes.  If you couldn&amp;rsquo;t meet your goals for a task put a smaller colorful post-it on it - as an ALERT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Address the needs of problem tasks&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; for all tasks with an ALERT: write emails to get help, or make notes on research needed to do make progress on problem tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REFLECT&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Assess what is going well and consider if doing more that will help you be more successful and assess what is hindering you and what you can do differently to get you work done with less stress.  You reflections should result in actions (experiments for a week or so) to help you move more effectively toward your goals.  If your experiment doesn&amp;rsquo;t help, they after the test period try a new experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Dead person&lt;/strong&gt; activities are actions that even a dead person can successfully do.  For example, waiting for someone else to help, not checking twitter in homework time, etc.
&lt;strong&gt;Live person&lt;/strong&gt; activities are action that only live people can successfully accomplish. For example, ask a peer for help, research on the Internet for ideas, go to a help session, replace random twitter checks with Pomodoro Technique (and allow twitter in the 5 minute breaks), etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;kanban&#34;&gt;Kanban&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.personalkanban.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.personalkanban.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://moduscooperandi.com/books-and-classes&#34;&gt;https://moduscooperandi.com/books-and-classes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;pomodoro&#34;&gt;Pomodoro&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://francescocirillo.com/pages/pomodoro-technique&#34;&gt;https://francescocirillo.com/pages/pomodoro-technique&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VFW3Ld7JO0w&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VFW3Ld7JO0w&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;helpful-books&#34;&gt;Helpful Books&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kanban - Task Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Real-World Kanban: Do Less, Accomplish More with Lean Thinking, by Mattias Skarin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kanban in Action, by Marcus Hammarberg and Joakim Sundén.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kanban: Successful Evolutionary Change for Your Technology Business, by David J. Anderson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal Kanban: Mapping Work - Navigating Life, by Tonianne DeMaria Barry and Jim Benson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kanban and Scrum: Making the Most of Both, by Mattias Skarin and Henrik Kniberg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pomodoro - Time Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pomodoro Technique Illustrated, by Staffan Noteberg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Pomodoro Technique: Work smarter, not harder, by Francesco Cirillo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Effective Reflections, Experiments &amp;amp; Problem Solving&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 5 Elements of Effective Thinking, by Edward B. Burger and Michael Starbird.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the shibumi strategy: a powerful way to create MEANINGFUL CHANGE, by Matthew E. May.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Effective Goal Setting &amp;amp; Changes - with small easy steps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Little Bets: How Breakthrough Ideas Emerge from Small Discoveries, by Peter Sims.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One Small Step Can Change Your Life: The Kaizen Way Paperback, by Robert Maurer Ph.D.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Spirit of Kaizen: Creating Lasting Excellence One Small Step at a Time: Creating Lasting Excellence One Small Step at a Time, by Robert Maurer Ph.D.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
