<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | btihen</title>
    <link>https://btihen.me/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://btihen.me/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 01:20:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://btihen.me/img/btihen_landing_page.png</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>https://btihen.me/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Tihen</title>
      <link>https://btihen.me/authors/btihen/_index_original_bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://btihen.me/authors/btihen/_index_original_bio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developer, Educator, Meditator and Nature Enthusiast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hold a Masters in Electrical Engineering (with a focus on Materials Science). I also have a ScrumMaster certification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have worked as a robotics designer, teacher, systems administrator and software engineer. My technical work has strongly influenced how I teach: Research and Agile practices have helped me develop a keen interest in the joy of exploring or &amp;lsquo;playful experiments.&amp;rsquo; Agile presents the Plan, Do, Reflect, Adjust loop and I have found that  &amp;lsquo;smallifying&amp;rsquo; large tasks is an effective way to make progress with a large overwhelming project. In fact, taking little exploratory &amp;lsquo;bets&amp;rsquo; / experiments to move forward, helps many people feel safe. When I realized these are also excellent learning methodologies, I realized in addition to content, I need to teach these skills too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time I have also realized that one of the most important aspects of a classroom (or work environment) is that it is exciting, engaging and generally an uplifting environment.  Or possibly an energy gifting experience. I have found the when students can choose their learning outcomes &amp;amp; goals (within the expectations of the class curriculum) the classroom can offer students these experiences too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
